### Effective Date: June 5, 2018

Financial Times Pro
-------------------

This Privacy Policy explains how Financial Times Pro (hereinafter referred to as "Company," "us," "our," or "we") collects, uses and transfers consumer information collected on FinancialTimesPro.com (the "Site").

Please note that we review our privacy practices from time to time, and that our practices are subject to change. We ask that you bookmark and periodically review this page to ensure continuing familiarity with the most current version of our Privacy Policy. All revisions shall be automatically effective after they are posted on the Site. Please check the Effective Date above to note when the Privacy Policy was last updated.

By visiting the Site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use or access the Site.

This Privacy Policy will tell you, among other things:

[California notice regarding categories, sources and business and commercial uses of information](#californianotice)  

Click on any of the above links to go directly to the corresponding section of this Privacy Policy.

### NOTICE OF COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

This Policy provides notice to users, including those who are California residents and fall within the definition of “consumers” as provided for in the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”), that we collect Information. As required by the CCPA, the following sections of the Policy also details the categories and sources of Information collected and the business and commercial purposes for the collected Information. We also include a description of rights afforded to California consumers at “RIGHTS OF CALIFORNIA USERS WITH REGARD TO THEIR INFORMATION” including rights to know the Information we have collected and sold and the right to opt-out from the sale of Information and the right to deletion.

### COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

We collect and combine personally identifiable information ("PII") and non-personally identifiable information ("Non-PII") through various sources, including those discussed below. For your reference, PII is data collected with an intention to specifically identify, contact, or locate a person, including but not limited to name, address, telephone number, or email address. On the other hand, Non-PII is data that is not used to specifically identify, contact or locate an individual, including but not limited to gender, age, or IP address.

Your email will only be shared with our preferred mailing partner for the purpose of sending third party promotional email communication.

Information we collect on the Site includes, but may not be limited to the following:

#### Site Registration Form

Types of information collected:

* email address
* first name
* last name
* street address
* city, state, and zip code
* phone number(s)
* date of birth

#### Survey Questions & Offer Forms

The Site may contain various survey questions. When you answer a survey question, we may transfer some or all of the information you submitted during the registration process to advertisers that we believe (based on your answer) may be of interest to you without providing you with another opportunity to review the information.

We also collect information about you when you complete an offer form on the Site. Please note that we may pre-fill offer forms with the information you submitted during the registration process for your convenience.

#### Automatic Information/Digital Identifiers

We may automatically receive and store certain types of information about you through the data sources listed above. You may be familiar with the term "cookies," which are unique alphanumeric identifiers that store information on your computer. A cookie is placed on your computer when your web browser accesses the Site. We use cookies for tracking transactions and the user characteristics explained in detail throughout this Privacy Policy. If you choose, there are utilities available for purchase from independent software providers to install on your computer, as well as tools/preferences you can choose through most web browsers to make website visits anonymous.

We also collect information through our web server applications. This information includes your Internet Protocol or "IP" address, date/time stamp, browser type, and referring URL. Additionally, we may use pixel tracking technology to track the completion of transactions with us or our advertisers, the source information for those transactions, and your IP address, date/time stamp, browser type, and referring URL.

### HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We may use the information we collect, including PII, for the following purposes:

* To contact you for marketing and promotional purposes by various means, including email, text and phone;
* To pre-fill or pre-populate offer forms on the Site;
* To send and/or display targeted advertisements;
* To respond to inquiries submitted to us;
* To enhance our database;
* To validate the data we have in our database;
* To detect violations of applicable policies, laws, rules, and/or regulations; and
* For any other purposes that Company deems appropriate.

### HOW WE DISCLOSE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We may disclose the information we collect, including PII, as described below:

* Corporate Affiliates. We may disclose the information we collect to our corporate affiliates.
* Service Providers. We may disclose the information we collect to third party vendors, service providers, contractors, and/or agents who perform services on our behalf, including but not limited to email service providers, data hygiene services, suppression services, compliance services, and backup services.
* Marketing Partners. We may disclose the information we collect to third party marketing partners to contact you via email, text, and/or phone, and to serve offers to you.
* Advertisers. We may disclose information we collect to advertisers who hire us to promote their products, services, and/or websites.
* Data Appending and Validation. We may share information we collect with third parties to append information to other data points we have in our database and/or to validate the data we have in our database.
* Business Transfers. If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if part or all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected to another company or entity.
* Legal Reasons. We may disclose the information we collect in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a subpoena or in response to a request from a government agency.
* To Protect the Company and Others. We may disclose the information we collect where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety or property of any person, or violation of any of our policies or procedures.
* Aggregate and De-identified Information. We may share aggregate, anonymous, or de-identified information with third parties for marketing, advertising, research, or other purposes.
* For any other purposes that Company deems appropriate.

Please note that some of these recipients may be outside of the United States.

### CALIFORNIA NOTICE REGARDING CATEGORIES, SOURCES AND BUSINESS AND COMMERCIAL USES OF INFORMATION

The following chart contains the categories of information, as enumerated in CCPA Sec. 1798.140(o), of Information we collect, use, disclose and sell, the sources of the Information and our business and commercial uses of such Information:

|     |     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Category** | **Category Name/Description** | **1\. Sources** | **2\. Business Use** | **3\. Commercial Use** |
| A   | Identifiers - name, postal, email and IP address, telephone number | User provided on registration, customer service inquiries and claim forms; related and 3rd party sources to verify and/or augment user supplied information | Operational purposes including determining survey questions, optional offers and deals to be displayed; customer service; fraud & security incidence detection; pre-population of user forms; website improvement | Sold to third parties for marketing purposes; shared with third parties to determine deals to be offered and to pre-populate order forms |
| B   | Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute – Identifiers and education, employment medical and health information | As above, plus user responses to survey questions | Same as 2. A | Same as 3. A and to target sales of Information to third parties |
| C   | Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law - Age, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex and related medical conditions | Same as 1. B | Same as 2. A | Same as 3. B |
| D   | Commercial information - products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing data | User provided customer service inquires and claim forms, from 3rd party advertisers and system collected website activity logs | Same as 2. A and to determine entitlement to rewards and amounts owed by advertisers and data purchasers | Determine amounts owed by advertisers and data buyers and performance of data campaigns |
| E   | Internet or similar network activity -browsing and search history, information on a consumer's interaction with a website, application, or advertisement | System collected activity logs and cookies | Same as 2. A and to determine (i) whether user is a repeat visitor; (ii) performance of and amounts owed to paid media suppliers; and (iii) support proof of user consent for email marketing and TCPA purposes | Same as 3. D |
| F   | Inferences drawn from other personal information - profile reflecting a person's preferences, characteristics, psychological trends and attitudes | Same as 1. B and system algorithms | Same as 2. A | None |

### RIGHTS OF CALIFORNIA USERS WITH REGARD TO THEIR INFORMATION

California users have several rights regarding the collection, use, disclosure and sale of their information under the CCPA. One of these rights, notice of collection of Information, is described above; the balance of these rights are described below and include the following rights:

* Disclosure of information collected and sold
* Opt-out from the sale of Information
* Deletion of Information
* Access and portability of Information collected
* Non-discrimination

### WHY YOU RECEIVE MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS

When you registered on the Site, you agreed to receive emails, texts and phone calls from the Site, its advertisers and marketing partners.

### HOW YOU CAN STOP RECEIVING MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS

To unsubscribe from further emails from the Site, **[click here](http://www.ninewesttech.com/o-thbc-h92-30b570a704970615ff377eac24e785fa)**.

If you do not wish to receive additional commercial emails from the applicable advertiser, utilize the unsubscribe mechanism in the email and follow the instructions to unsubscribe your email address. Please note that it may take up to ten (10) business days to process your request and that the unsubscribe request is limited to the applicable advertiser.

If you no longer wish to receive text messages, follow the instructions in the applicable text.

If you no longer wish to receive telephone calls, convey that information to the applicable seller.

### PUSH NOTIFICATIONS

You may allow us to send you push notifications. We use push notifications to send you notifications related to our advertisers. Your browser or device settings should provide you with instructions on how to turn off push notifications.

### HOW YOU CAN SEEK CORRECTIONS TO YOUR INFORMATION

You may request modification of any personal data we have collected about you by contacting us at: [financialtimespro@financialtimespro.com](mailto:financialtimespro@financialtimespro.com)

### HOW WE SECURE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

While we strive to protect your data from unauthorized use or disclosure, we do not warrant or guarantee the security of your data.

### THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

By using this website, you grant express prior consent for your data to be shared with third party technology providers, including those using session replay technology. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third party websites, including those promoted by the emails sent to you or the offers served to you. You should check the privacy and security policy statements of third party websites to understand their policies and practices. This Privacy Policy is limited to information collected on the Site.

### INFORMATION ABOUT CHILDREN

The Site is not intended to be used by children under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personal information from, or target the Site or our services to, children under the age of 18.

### HOW TO SUBMIT A QUESTION OR COMPLAINT

Questions or complaints about this Privacy Policy or how we collect, use or disclose information in connection with the Site should be directed to [financialtimespro@financialtimespro.com](mailto:financialtimespro@financialtimespro.com).

We will review your question or complaint and respond if and how we deem appropriate.
